Records of the Athletics Department RG.41
New York University Archives
- RG 41.11: Tennis, 1919-1976
  Series 41.11 contains the records pertaining to the tennis team. Men's tennis began at NYU in 1907, and women's tennis began in 1923. The records within this series range from 1919-1976 and contain tennis records, rosters, schedules, press releases, and clippings.
  Men's and women's tennis results for 1983-2014 are located in Archives H.
  - Tennis All-Time Records, 1919-1955 (Box 43, Folder 1)
  - Tennis Schedules, 1945-1946 (Box 43, Folder 2)
  - Tennis Schedules, 1946-1947 (Box 43, Folder 3)
  - Tennis Roster and Press Releases, 1948 (Box 43, Folder 4)
  - Tennis Press Information, 1950 (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - Tennis Press Information, 1952 (Box 43, Folder 6)
  - Tennis Correspondence, 1954-1955 (Box 43, Folder 7)
  - Tennis Schedule, 1956-1957 (Box 43, Folder 8)
  - Tennis Press Information, 1958-1962 (Box 43, Folder 9)
  - Tennis Clipping, 1963 (Box 43, Folder 10)
  - Tennis Press Information and Clippings, 1964 (Box 43, Folder 11)
  - Tennis Press Information and Clippings, 1965 (Box 43, Folder 12)
  - Tennis Press Information and Clippings, 1966 (Box 43, Folder 13)
  - Tennis Press Information and Clippings, 1967 (Box 43, Folder 14)
  - Tennis Press Information and Clippings, 1968 (Box 43, Folder 15)
  - Tennis Press Information, 1969 (Box 43, Folder 16)
  - Tennis Press Information and Clippings, 1970 (Box 43, Folder 17)
  - Tennis Press Information and Clippings, 1970-1971 (Box 43, Folder 18)
  - Tennis Clippings, 1971 (Box 43, Folder 19)
  - Tennis Press Information and Clippings, 1975-1976 (Box 43, Folder 20)
  - Emerson, Gerald Biography, 1937-1939 (Box 43, Folder 21)
  - Henriquez, Carlos Biography, 1949 (Box 43, Folder 22)
  - Kurtz, Earl Biography, 1965 (Box 43, Folder 23)
- RG 41.12: Golf, 1930-1976
  History of Golf at NYU
  Golf became a varsity sport at NYU in 1930. Just nine years later, however, the team was dissolved. When it returned in 1954, the men went undefeated with victories over city rivals Manhattan College, St. John's University, and Columbia University. In the 1980s, the team used Riverdale Country Club in New Jersey for its home matches. The team competes at the Division III level in the University Athletic Association conference.
  Women's golf arrived at NYU in 2007.
  Men's golf results for 2000-2014 can be found in Archives H. Women's golf results for 2007-2014 can be found in Archives H.
  The golf team was started at New York University in 1930. The records for this team span 1930 to 1976 and contain player biographies, newspaper clippings, golf tournament programs, and NYU press releases.
  - Golf Metropolitan Championships, 1963 (Box 43, Folder 24)
  - Golf Press Information and Team Records, 1954 (Box 43, Folder 25)
  - Golf Press Information and Golf, 1956-1962 (Box 43, Folder 26)
  - Golf Press Information, 1963 (Box 43, Folder 27)
  - Golf Clippings and Press Information, 1964 (Box 43, Folder 28)
  - Golf Clippings and Press Information, 1965 (Box 43, Folder 29)
  - Golf Clippings and Press Information, 1966 (Box 43, Folder 30)
  - Golf Clippings and Press Information, 1967 (Box 43, Folder 31)
  - Golf Clippings and Press Information, 1968 (Box 43, Folder 32)
  - Golf Clippings and Press Information, 1969 (Box 43, Folder 33)
  - Golf Clippings and Press Information, 1969 (Box 43, Folder 33)
  - Golf Clippings and Press Information, 1970 (Box 43, Folder 34)
  - Golf Clippings and Press Information, 1970 (Box 43, Folder 35)
  - Golf Press Information, 1972 (Box 43, Folder 36)
  - Golf Team Equipment Record, 1973 (Box 43, Folder 37)
  - Pechar, Stanley Biography, 1960 (Box 43, Folder 38)
  - Penzetti, Al Biography, 1957 (Box 43, Folder 39)
  - Reissman, Jeff Biograph, 1972 (Box 43, Folder 40)
- RG 41.13: Soccer, 1958-1973 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  History of Soccer at NYU
  Soccer arrived at NYU in 1923 and was called "soccer football." The 1923 team had a winning season despite a lack of funds and a field on which to practice. In 1926, the program was terminated but returned in 1958 in an informal capacity. The team went undefeated in its first year back under the leadership of Coach Allan Towbin. Soccer returned to varsity status in 1959. The NYU soccer team continues to compete on the varsity level for both men and women in the University Athletics Association Conference.
  Series 41.13 is comprised of the records of the soccer team, including newspaper clippings, press information, team rosters, and player biographies ranging in date from 1958 to 1973. There is also some documentation from the initial iteration of the team in the 1920s.
  Men's soccer results for 1983-2014 can be found in Archives H. Women's soccer results for 1995-2014 can be found in Archives H.
  - Soccer Records, 1922-1967 (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - Freshman Soccer Results, 1959-1966 (Box 44, Folder 2)
  - Varsity Soccer Results, 1922-1926 (Box 44, Folder 3)
  - Soccer Club Records, 1958 (Box 44, Folder 4)
  - Soccer Press Information, 1959 (Box 44, Folder 5)
  - Soccer Clippings and Press Information, 1960 (Box 44, Folder 6)
  - Soccer Team Rosters, Press Information, and Clippings, 1961 (Box 44, Folder 1961)
  - Soccer Clippings and Press Information, 1962 (Box 44, Folder 8)
  - Soccer Clippings and Press Information, 1963 (Box 44, Folder 9)
  - Soccer Team Rosters, Press Information, and Clippings, 1964 (Box 44, Folder 10)
  - Soccer Clippings and Press Information, 1965 (Box 44, Folder 11)
  - Soccer Clippings, Press Information, and Awards, 1966 (Box 44, Folder 12)
  - Soccer Clippings and Press Information, 1967 (Box 45, Folder 1)
  - Soccer Clippings and Press Information, 1968 (Box 45, Folder 2)
  - Soccer Clippings and Press Information, 1969 (Box 45, Folder 3)
  - Soccer Clippings and Press Information, 1970 (Box 45, Folder 4)
  - Soccer Clippings and Press Information, 1971 (Box 45, Folder 5)
  - Soccer Clippings and Press Information, 1972 (Box 45, Folder 6)
  - Gestal, Robin Biography, 1972 (Box 45, Folder 7)
  - Killian, Frederick Biography, 1964 (Box 45, Folder 8)
  - Kish, Andrew Biograph, 1965-1968 (Box 45, Folder 9)
  - Larrea, Robert Biography, 1967 (Box 45, Folder 10)
  - Messing, Shep Biography, 1968-1969 (Box 45, Folder 11)
  - Ramirez, Arnold Biography, 1972 (Box 45, Folder 12)
  - Rossabi, Mayer Biography, 1962-1963 (Box 45, Folder 13)
  - Stover, James Biography, 1968 (Box 45, Folder 14)
  - Towbin, Allen Biography, 1958-1961 (Box 45, Folder 15)
  - Vargas, George Biography, 1964-1972 (Box 45, Folder 14)
  - Yellows Soccer, 1973 (Box 45, Folder 15)
- RG 41.14: Cross-Country
  Series 41.13 is comprised of the records of the Cross-Country Team
- RG 41.16: Swimming
  History of Swimming at NYU
  Men's and women's swimming became varsity sports in the 1920s. Swim meets were held at the University Heights campus until its closure in 1973. When the Coles Sport Center was completed in 1981, the teams had a new home near Washington Square. Both teams have had numerous winning seasons throughout the years and have produced a number of Olympians. The men's and women's swimming teams continue to compete at the Division III level of the NCAA.
  Series 41.13 is comprised of the records of the Swim Team.
  - Women's Swimming, 1945-1947 (Box 40, Folder 2)
  - Women's Swimming, 1959 (Box 40, Folder 3)
- RG 41.15: Diving
  Series 41.13 is comprised of the records of the Diving Team.
- RG 41.17: Volleyball
  Series 41.13 is comprised of the records of the Volleyball Team.
- RG 41.18: Wrestling
  History of Wrestling at NYU
  Wrestling became a varsity sport at NYU in 1934 under the direction of Olympian Charles Cranford. Interest declined the following season and the wrestling program went on hiatus until 1939. In the 1970s the NYU wrestlers topped the Metropolitan and Eastern rankings. The wrestling team competes today at the Division III level of the NCAA. They are a member of the University Athletic Association (UAA) Conference.
  Series 41.13 is comprised of the records of the Wrestling Team.
  - Varsity Wrestling, 1946-1947 (Box 40, Folder 4)
- RG 41.19: Softball
  Series 41.13 is comprised of the records of the Softball Team.
- RG 41.20: Bowling
  History of Bowling at NYU
  NYU briefly had an all-female bowling team that competed during the 1940s and 1950s.
  Series 41.13 is comprised of the records of the Bowling Team.
  - Women's Bowling, 1945-1947 (Box 40, Folder 5)
- RG 41.21: Riflery
  History of Riflery at NYU
  Riflery was brought back to NYU in 1929 after having been dissolved years earlier. The team practiced at ranges on the University Heights campus and had great successes during the 1930s. In 1931 the freshmen team was named the national intercollegiate champion. Riflery is no longer a competitive sport at NYU.
  Series 41.13 is comprised of the records of the Riflery Team.
  - Varsity Rifle, 1946-1947 (Box 40, Folder 6)
- RG 41.22: Field Hockey
  History of Field Hockey at NYU
  The NYU field hockey team played its first games in the 1924 season. This varsity team practiced at Central Park and Prospect Park. In 1931 the team played a game on the Ohio Field at University Heights, becoming the first female team to play on this field. Field hockey is no longer a competitive sport at NYU.
  Series 41.13 is comprised of the records of the Field Hockey Team.
  - Women's Field Hockey, 1945-1947 (Box 40, Folder 7)
- Unprocessed Materials (Box 232, Box 233, Box 234, Box 235)